At Airbnb, where you were before Coinbase,
在加入 coinbase 之前 你在 Airbnb 工作
can you talk about maybe like chains of command in terms of we have
你能跟我们谈一谈 Airbnb 组织架构是怎样的吗？
data analysts and this is the types of problems that they work on or even
比如说你们有数据分析师 他们一般都在解决什么样的问题
like we have data scientists that do this versus we have data scientists who do this,
或者说数据科学家 这个职位一般又是在做什么
and this is how we sort of differentiate maybe when
然后你们是如何区分这两个岗位的
you're hiring for them or the skill sets that we're looking for in those people.
以及你们在招聘的时候会看重哪些特质
One of the things definitely I would encourage anyone who's
我非常建议大家花时间了解一下
thinking about data science role is to try to disambiguate what it means,
数据科学这个词背后可能包含的不同工作类型
because it can mean a dozen different things and will change with
因为不同公司的数据科学家
every single company that is hiring data scientists.
可能都在做不同的跟数据相关的事情
So, I'll try to give some of the more specific ones first.
所以 我先说一些工作内容比较明确的岗位
So, often companies will have algorithms or machine learning data scientists.
很多公司会有偏重做算法和机器学习模型的数据科学家
They are specifically in charge of
他们主要负责优化那些
a very valuable algorithm that the company needs in order to survive.
对公司至关重要的算法
So, that might be for example a search algorithm.
比如说 搜索算法
At Airbnb when you type in a location,
在 Airbnb 里 如果你输入一个地点
like that ordered list is extremely influential to the business.
你得到的关于住宿的排序其实是非常关键的
There's a team of data scientists and engineers who work on that.
这个排序的算法 就是由一批数据科学家或者工程师们
That's like most of what they do.
负责做的
So, that sort of algorithms and data science or algorithms and machine learning.
也就是说 更偏向算法和机器学习
There's a kind of the role that
还有一种类型跟我们之前谈到的很像
we've just been talking about in terms of experimentation,
跟实验有关
which is saying all right we're looking to make these changes,
比如说 如果我们要做某些改变
what should we measure,
如何衡量最后的效果
how do we make sure the data lands in a place where it can be measured?
如何获取和整合这些数据
That sort of role which is a little bit of
这个类型的人才需要什么都懂一些
a generalist in terms of you need some statistics background,
比如说 你要有一些统计学的背景
you need to know some data engineering,
你还要懂一些数据工程
and also some of those communication skills that we're just talking about.
并且还要负责大量沟通
There's maybe even a third layer,
除此之外 还有另外一大类数据科学家
which is more concentrated on high-level business analysis.
他们更注重高层次的商业分析
Starting to get more even towards financial planning analysis roles or
他们可能会做财务分析
business analysts and that
或者商业分析
might be termed data analyst or might be termed data scientists,
他们有时候被叫数据分析师 有时候也被叫数据科学家
but at that point you're thinking about these high level metrics,
主要考虑一些比较高层次的指标
the right cuts for those metrics,
设定这些指标的阀值
the display for those metrics to executives or
并把这些指标展现给管理层或者产品经理
other business leaders and making sure that for example we know when those things change,
并且确保在指标发生改变之后 他们可以第一时间知道
can explain what happened,
而且还能对这种变化进行解释
those sorts of questions.
之类的工作
Super insightful. Can you talk
说得非常好 你能再讲一讲
about maybe the toolkits that those people have and how they're different?
不同类型的数据科学们各自会使用的工具吗
So, like one of the first algorithms person is that like,
比如第一类做算法的数据科学家
you need to know C++, you need to have like really strong CS skills.
他们可能需要掌握 C++ 并且具备非常厉害的工程能力
Then the second is maybe more Python.
第二类可能更多地会使用 Python
Then the third one almost sounds like even tools,
而最后一类 他们可能不会使用任何编程语言
like dashboard tools like Tableau and things like that.
而使用一些类似 Tableau 的工具
Is that the toolkits or are there different tools that you've seen used in those roles?
还有其他的软件包或者工具吗？
For example on the machine learning side,
如果你是做机器学习
you're going to see different tools used across the board.
你很可能也会用到其他的工具
So, you definitely see more things like C++ in places
但是 C++ 是一定会用到的
where they need extremely good performance or maybe embedded devices.
因为你需要用 C++ 来提高程序的执行效率 比如在一些嵌入式设备上
Autonomous driving being pretty clear recent example.
自动驾驶就是一个经典的例子
But that might also be people using something like
其他的话 就是类似 Scikit-learn
Scikit-learn or TensorFlow or any of those sorts of Python tools for example.
或者 TensorFlow 或者其他具有 Python 接口的工具包
The general stroll you'd assume more,
至于第二个类数据科学家
I guess for both generalist and machine learning you
我想跟第一类一样
see some of that data engineering toolkit,
他们也需要掌握数据工程类的工具
which are both the abstraction layers like airflow and
比如像 airflow 这样的抽象框架
also the sort of underlying engines which are things like distributed SQL engines,
或底层的类似分布式 SQL 这样的引擎
Hive, Presto, also things like Spark,
例如 Hive Presto 或 Spark Flink
Flink these sorts of jobs,
掌握这些工具
so that you can get the data you need and put it where you need to be.
你才能把你想要的数据放到合适的地方
Then you see more of the analysis and visualization layer for the high-level picture,
最后就是更偏向于分析和可视化的
which could be dashboarding tools like Tableau, Looker, Superset.
类似于 Tableau  Looker  Superset 这些工具都很受欢迎
Then data access layer is probably SQL,
获取数据的话 可能就是用 SQL
but there's some other options too.
当然 也会有其他的选择
Cool.
好的